cityofpaloalto.org 2009-11-09

# City of Palo Alto Website - Web Site Help

Web Site Help  

Choose your comment type  
  
---  
  
Web Site Comments 

Use the Web Site Comment form if... 

  * You would like to report a broken link
  * You have a problem viewing a page 
  * You would like to relate your opinion
  * You would like to make a suggestion

If you can't find what you are looking for, and believe that important content is missing from the web site, please submit a Web SIte Content Request. 

| 

Web Site Content Request 

Use the Web Site Content Request form if... 

  * You can't find what you're looking for
  * You believe information is incorrectly classified on the site
  * Information is incomplete or unclear 

If your comment seems more technical in nature, or is not specifically about the information content on the web site, please use the Web Site Comments form.   

| 

Contact by Telephone 

  * Link to the Phone Directory
  * Link to the Emergency Information "Whom to Contact" Page  

Browser 

Best viewed in 1024x768, Internet Explorer 7.

Search Engine 

Search is a crucial component of the City of Palo Alto web site. Search provides connectivity to all web site file types, News Details, Departmental PDFs, Minutes, Agendas and Reports, and Contacts for easy and quick aggregated searching of all web site documents. When a citizen, business, or municipality needs information or services that don't emerge through site navigation, search often provides the most efficient path to the desired result. 

Our Family Resources pages provide a traditional and indexed search of Palo Alto community resources. Traditional search offers many filters and lists to help you identify the type of resources you desire. Additionally Family Resources offers a categorical search based on the industry-standard InfoLine taxonomy.

Your Privacy 

Privacy Notice Information   
The City of Palo Alto Administrative Services, Information Technology Division, developed and manages this web site. This web site is the gateway for providing direct government-to-citizen public service provision and interaction through the use of information technology. We are dedicated to protecting your privacy on-line. The following privacy statement outlines how individual information will be handled by the City of Palo Alto while using this site. 

Information Collected and Stored Automatically   
For site management functions, information is collected for analysis and statistical purposes. This information is not reported or used in any manner that would reveal personally identifiable information, and will not be released to any outside parties unless legally required to do so in connection with law enforcement investigations or other legal proceedings. 

We use Log analysis tools to create summary statistics, which are used for purposes such as assessing what information is of most interest, determining technical design specifications, and identifying system performance or problem areas. Our Web site logs do not collect personally identifiable information, and we make no attempt to link them with the individuals who browse the web site. When you visit the City of Palo Alto web site and browse or download information, we automatically collect and store the following information about your visit: 

  * The Internet Protocol Address and domain name used but not the email address. The Internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the Internet Protocol Address to direct Internet traffic to you; 
  * The type of browser and operating system you used; 
  * The date and time you visited this site; 
  * The Web pages or services you accessed at this site; and 
  * The Web site you visited prior to coming to this Web site. 

If during your visit to the City of Palo Alto Web Site you participate in a survey, fill out a Web form, or send an email, the following additional information will be collected: 

  * The email address and contents of the email; and 
  * Information volunteered to complete a Web form or in response to a survey. 

If you send us an email with a question or comment that contains personally identifiable information, or fill out a form that emails us this information, we will only use the personally identifiable information to respond to your request and analyze trends. This may be to respond to you, to address issues you identify, or to further improve our Web site. We may redirect your message to another department, division or program within the City that is in a better position to answer your question. Survey information is used only for the purpose designated. 

Personal Information and Choice   
"Personal information" is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as an individual's name, address, and phone number. A domain name or Internet Protocol address is not considered personal information. 

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily participate in an activity that asks for information (i.e. sending an email, filling out a Web form, or participating in a survey). If you choose not to participate in these activities, your choice will in no way affect your ability to use any other feature of this web site.

If personal information is requested on the Web site or volunteered by the user, State law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it. However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by Federal or State law. 

Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children on-line or by email will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access. 

Public Disclosure 

In the State Of California, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by municipalities. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals. Exceptions are provided by both State and Federal laws.

All information collected at this site becomes public records that may be subject to inspection and copying by the public, unless an exemption in law exists. 

Cookies   
This web site uses "cookies" to customize your browsing experience with the City of Palo Alto web site. A cookie contains unique information a web site can use to track such things as the Internet Protocol address for the computer you used to access this site, the identification of the browser software and operating system you used, the date and time you accessed the site, and the Internet address of the website from which you linked to this site. Cookies created on your computer by using this web site do not contain personally identifying information and do not compromise your privacy or security. You can refuse the cookie or delete the cookie file from your computer by using any of the widely available methods. If you choose not to accept a cookie on your computer, it will not prevent or prohibit you from gaining access to or using this site. 

Security , Intrusion, Detection Language   
The Division of Information Technology, as developer and manager of the City of Palo Alto web site, has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its telecommunications and computing infrastructure, including but not limited to authentication, monitoring, auditing and encryption. Security measures have been integrated into the design, implementation and day-to-day practices of the entire web site operating environment as part of its continuing commitment to risk management. This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof, the security of information provided via the City's web site. 

Unauthorized attempts to deny service, upload information, change information, or to attempt to access a non-public site from this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under Title 18 of the U.S. Code to include the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act. 

Acceptable Use 

Using the City of Palo Alto web site indicates your agreement with our web site RULES which contain important CONDITIONS AND RESTRICTIONS. If you do not agree, please refrain from using this web site. 

Individuals, organizations and businesses are free to use the City of Palo Alto web site for any lawful, worthy and ethical purpose, except as limited by these Rules. The web site must not be used to solicit customers or sell products or services. 

Users with "robots," "spiders," or other automated programs may visit the City of Palo Alto web site, but are prohibited from resending or redirecting information without the prior written permission of the City of Palo Alto. 

We ask all web site users to use appropriate names and language in the name spaces, address spaces and other spaces (if any) provided on the web site. Users are forbidden from using false e-mail addresses. 

This web site contains material protected by law, including but not limited to copyrights and trademarks. All rights in such material are reserved to the City of Palo Alto and materials may not be reused in any way or copied in whole or part without prior written permission from the City of Palo Alto. 

No representations or warranties are made regarding the materials in or Operations of this web site. In particular, the City of Palo Alto makes no warranties concerning the integrity or fitness or a particular purpose of any information, either express or implied, and disclaims any warranties of non-infringement. The City of Palo Alto shall not be liable for any damages of any kind that may result from the use of this web site. Materials in and operations of this web site are provided as-is and there is no warranty made that they will be free from errors or interruptions. Any liability of the City of Palo Alto to users for any damages or losses of any kind shall not exceed the amount paid by the user, if any, for use of this web site. 

These rules represent the entire agreement between users and the City of Palo Alto and may not be modified except by a signed written agreement. This agreement shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of the State of California. If any provision of these rules shall be declared by a court to be invalid, illegal, or unenforceable, such provision shall be deemed severable from this agreement and the other provisions shall remain in full force and effect. 

Accessibility 

The City of Palo Alto web site is designed to offer Palo Alto citizens and businesses easy and efficient access to municipal resources. We appreciate that many visitors to our web site are concerned about accessibility to digital government. Currently, we make every effort to adhere to 508 requirements as set forth by the W3C Accessibility Initiative. Ongoing validation testing is conducted using industry-recognized tools for coding and usability. 

The "Text Version" of this web site is optimized for screen readers, and other text-based web interfaces.

Please submit a comment, using the form above, if there is information on this web site you are having trouble accesing.

Disclaimer 

This web site has links to other web sites. These include links to web sites operated by other government agencies, other cities, nonprofit organizations and private businesses. When you link to another site, you are no longer on The City of Palo Alto Web Site and this Privacy Notice is not applicable. When you link to another Web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. 

Neither the City of Palo Alto, nor any agency, officer, or employee warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at his or her own risk.
